https://www.linkedin.com/in/mirazmanji/ • 416-587-1728 • mirazmanji@gmail.com

To Whom It May Concern:

As a well-established IT leader with a passion for innovation, project management, data engineering, design, software development, and working with high performing people, I am an ideal candidate to join a forward thinking leadership team. Having achieved tremendous success administering a thriving technology-driven business for more than 12 years, teaching and mentoring junior engineers, and developing algorithms in the Banking industry, I am intrigued by opportunities to apply my skills to build superior products while being a good corporate citizen to the benefit of all stakeholders in your organization.

Throughout my career, I have made it my priority to utilize current technologies and new techniques to develop elegant, creative technical solutions across all project phases. Comfortable in collaborative and independently-driven roles, I am a forward-thinking business leader with refined analytical and critical thinking skills, and I can adapt and revise my strategies to meet evolving priorities, shifting needs, and emergent issues.

Furthermore, I would bring the following strengths to your team:

- Outside of the box innovator, intuitive people manager, and award winning entrepreneur.
- Excellent communicator and quick learner, committed to achieving all organizational goals.
- Certified Data Science Methodologist.
- Trained Information Security professional and Cloud Computing champion.
- Senior project management skills seasoned from thousands of design focused projects.
- Extensive experience leading the development of cutting-edge IT business solutions using AI, Machine Learning, and Application Programming Interfaces.
- High throughput engineer with 13,251 lines of production ready code written during lockdown.

I look forward to discussing my background and your needs in detail, as I am confident that my unique experience will be of great use in meeting your immediate and future objectives. Please contact me at your earliest convenience to schedule an interview; until then, thank you for your consideration.

Sincerely,
Miraz Manji
Enclosure

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mirazmanji/ • 416-587-1728 • mirazmanji@gmail.com

Innovation Leader, Full Stack Machine Learning Product Engineer

Taught Software Development, Received Leadership Invite on a Full Scholarship from Next Canada,

Named the Toronto Region Board of Trade Emerging Entrepreneur of the Year & Closed a Strategic Acquisition.

Senior software engineer & data scientist at TD Bank. Data engineering champion with a business mindset.

SKILLS

Advanced Proficiency:

Python, Java, JavaScript, JQuery, SQL, MYSQL, JSON, AJAX, XML, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, REST APIs. Google Analytics, Salesforce, Hootsuite, MS Office, Adobe CS5, Automations,

Windows, Mac., Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform

Intermediate Proficiency: Pandas, Scikit Learn, MatPlotLib, Numpy, Scala, SpaCy, Jupyter, Zeppelin, Tensorflow, Kubernetes, Virtual Machines, Kerberos, Hadoop, Spark, Spring, JSView, React, ESNext, Node.JS, Bash, Powershell, NOSQL, YAML, SOAP, Raspberry Pi, Service Now, Jenkins, WP

Core, C, Linux, Bootstrap, Flask, GUnicorn, NGinx, Apache, Git, Natural Language Programming, NLP Ai, BitBucket, Jira, OAuth, Identity Access Mgt, Google Suite

Expert Skills:

Market Data Analysis, People Management, Cold Calling, Sales, Teaching, Entrepreneurship

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer III, Data Scientist (01-2019 to Present)

TD Bank, Mississauga, ON

- Creating APIs for improving operation speed in the banking environment.
- Building secure solutions with Tensorflow & AutoML to create actionable insights.
- Developing client facing & server-side solutions in Python, Bash, Java Script, HTML, CSS, & SQL.
- Applying data science to big data to further the development of Machine Learning projects.
- Engineering microservices to handle highly sensitive work for DevOps & Cybersecurity units.
- Developing API based automations that are saving over 10,000 hours of work per year.
- Supporting Network, DevOps, & Database teams to enhance automations & improve efficiency
- Documenting & deploying solutions according to SDLC, Agile, & Scrum methodologies.

Machine Learning Engineer, SDE, Head of Product, (08-2018 to Present) Autoflow Inc., Toronto ON

- Creating APIs for managing operations in the manufacturing environment
- Developed automations for print manufacturers yielding a 110% customer success rate.
- Designing a scalable cloud based platform to process thousands of automations with zero bugs.
- Prototyping in specialized languages to further the development of Ai/Machine Learning projects.
- Managing juniors and scaling cloud infrastructure from startup levels to support mass adoption.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mirazmanji/ • 416-587-1728 • mirazmanji@gmail.com

Page Two

Advanced Web Development Instructor (07-2018 to 01-2019)

Red Academy, Toronto, ON

- Taught new developers from the ground up leading to a 90% hire rate.
- Impacted prospective students which increased enrolment by 100%.
- Teaching Javascript, ES6, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, & PHP.
- Instructing Digital Marketing, UI, & UX students to improve comprehensive understanding.
- Leading scrums, debugging code, & creating experiential as well as lecture-based experiences.
- Hiring & onboarding developers as teaching assistants to augment the student experience.
- Invigilating & marking entrance exams to maintain program integrity.
- Harmoniously managing a team of adult developers at different levels of technical competence.
- Cross collaborating in an agency environment & across multiple time zones.
- Collaboratively closing sales & designing solutions to enhance the program experience.

Founder, Product Manager, Software & Sales Engineer (05-2005 to 08-2018) TLAC Inc., Toronto, ON

- Founded, managed, & modernized an online print publishing & digital services company.
- Built 5 prototypes using bleeding edge machine learning and sensor technologies which led to being awarded the Toronto Region Board of Trade Emerging Entrepreneur of the Year in 2015.
- Developed software using the latest cloud infrastructure & programming languages leading to a niche competitive advantage & the highest customer satisfaction rating globally within the market.
- Executed strategies to reduce costs by 30% through software development. remote work, & workflow optimization; adroitly leveraged SEO & SMO to reach #1 organic rank worldwide.
- Engineered massive growth by increasing company sales ten-fold over a period of 7 years.
- Established an enterprise value of over \$1M & led the acquisition to a larger competitor.
- Led business & software to above market value acquisition by a highly-prominent organization.
- Led negotiations of Plant, Property, Human Resources, Partners, & Equipment leading to the leanest costs in the industry with the highest calibre of talent.

Director of Fundraising (08-2007 to 06-2011)

Seeds of Hope Foundation, Toronto, ON

- Created branded fundraising events which led to a sustainable source of charitable revenues.
- Led campaigns raising awareness on Homelessness & the need for Women's recovery shelters.

Software Instructor – Java Programming (08-2002 to 05-2003) University of Toronto, Toronto, ON

- Recognized for technical talent & coaching abilities which led to being appointed to officially lead tutorials during my undergraduate studies in a position reserved for computer science graduates.
- Teaching linked data structures, encapsulation, & information-hiding techniques in JAVA.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mirazmanji/ • 416-587-1728 • mirazmanji@gmail.com

Page Three

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Bachelor of Commerce with Distinction, Secondary Education in Computer Science

University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, 2002-2007

- Top Entrepreneurial Business Student as reported in the Globe & Mail
- Scored the highest cohort mark in a senior-level course: Management Information Systems
- Awarded 100% bursary grant for second year Computer Science Studies based on academic merit

Professional Development

- ✓ Family services & emotionally focused counselling, (2007-2013)
- ✓ Masters Leadership Program Harvard & MIT c/o Next Canada, Next Founders, (2014)
- ✓ Self directed online learning & a variety of Continuing Education courses, (2007 Present)
 - Mobile Application Development
 - Design Management
 - Game Development
 - Internet of Things DIY Projects

Notable Awards & Achievements

- √ Awarded University Teaching Position for Java Programming in Second Year Studies (2003)
- ✓ Invited to Next Canada's MIT / Harvard Leadership Institute on Full Scholarship (2014)
- ✓ Toronto Region Board of Trade Emerging Entrepreneur of the Year (2015)
- ✓ Featured in numerous online media publications including ZDNet & Notable (2016)
- ✓ Software & Startup Acquired (2018)
- ✓ Promoted to Solutions Engineer supporting Network, Database, & Ops teams at TD Bank (2020)
- ✓ 13,251 lines of production ready code written during Covid lockdown (2020)

Technical Certifications

- ✓ Fundamentals in Cyber Security (York University, 2018, Grade A+)
- ✓ Google Cloud Platform Core Infrastructure (Coursera, 2020, Grade A+)
- ✓ Data Science Methodology (Coursera, 2020, Grade A+)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Hobbies & Interests

Capital Markets, Coding, Sales, Music, Martial Arts, Mentoring, History, Japanese Language

Volunteering

- Director of Fundraising, Seeds of Hope (2007-2011)
- Guest Lecturer, University of Toronto (2016) & Ryerson University (2017)
- Various Mentoring & Private Instruction (2008-Present)

To Whom it May Concern,

I am pleased to provide a formal reference for Miraz Manji in support of his career in technology engineering and product management. I have had the pleasure of knowing Miraz for over ten years, having worked with him on various software development and startup projects – ranging from industry-focused solutions to agile training software.

Miraz is a high performing individual who works tirelessly at innovating processes, developing code, and finding ways to introduce new concepts to his colleagues. I have been consistently impressed by Miraz's teaching and management abilities combined with a unique blend of technical skills. A more recent project involved Miraz leading the development of an Al-based training application, demonstrating a proven ability to develop a cutting-edge piece of software supported by a pragmatic business case and go-to-market strategy.

Apart from his strong business acumen, Miraz is honest, straightforward, and possesses strong family values – the mark of a people-focused leader. He is loyal to his teammates and is always looking for new ways to improve the quality of his work and the value he delivers to his clients.

I highly recommend Miraz for a position in technology engineering and product management and believe he would be a valued asset in the workplace.

Sincerely,

Christopher Chadwick Global Director BlackBerry